Barbara McClintock Papers 1927-1991 Mss.Ms.Coll.79
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Works by McClintock, 1944-1989; 5 linear feet
  - University of California at Davis Lectures, Oct. 1964 (Box 20)
  - The Versatility of a Control System -- Lecture at University of Texas, Feb. 1968 (Box 20)
  - The Versatility of a Control System in Maize -- Seminar at University of Rochester, 19 Apr. 1968 (Box 20)
  - Versatility of Genetic Mechanisms -- Lecture at Cornell University, Mar. 1969 (Box 20)
  - Versatility of Genetic Systems in Eukaryotic Organisms -- Lecture at Duke University, 23 Feb. 1971 (Box 20)
  - The Versatility of the Genome in Eukaryotic Organisms -- Seminar at Albert Einstein College of Medicine, 10 Mar. 1969 (Box 20)
  - Why a Geneticist Became Fascinated With Some of Our Local Plants -- Lecture, 18-May-71 (Box 20)
- Series IV. Works by others, 1927-1991; 4.5 linear feet
  Articles, notes, reports, and papers written by colleagues and students of McClintock. This series is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title. This series attests to McClintock's practice of keeping up-to-date with the work of others in her field. Many authors are represented by four or more manuscripts, including Bruce Alberts, Guenter Albrecht-Buehler, Almiro Blumenschein, R. Alexander Brink, Benjamin Burr, Paul S. Chomet, Nina Fedoroff, Takeo A. Kato Yamakake, Frederick Meins, Jr., Oliver E. Nelson, Jr., Kenneth Paigen, Drew Schwartz, James A. Shapiro, David F. Weber, and Susan R. Wessler. Cross-references are given for photographs, which appear in this series. Also in this series are notes that McClintock took about works by others; her notes appear with the work or with a copy of the title page if it is a reprint.
  - A Model for Chromatin Based Upon Two Symmetrically Paired Half Nucleosomes, 1976; Alberts, Bruce (Box 21)
  - On the Biological Implications of Chromatin Structure, 1976; Alberts, Bruce, Abraham Worcel, and Harold Weintraub (Box 21)
  - Reconstruction of the T4 Bacteriophage DNA Replication Apparatus From Purified Components, n.d.; Alberts, Bruce, C. Fred Morris, David Mace, et al. (Box 21)
  - Steroid Receptors: Elements For Modulation of Eukaryotic Transcription, 1976; Alberts, Bruce and Keith R. Yamamoto (Box 21)
  - The Autonomous Movements of Cytoplasmic Fragments, n.d.; Albrecht-Buehler, Guenter (Box 21)
  - Is Cytoplasm Intelligent, Too?, [1983]; Albrecht-Buehler, Guenter (Box 21)
  - Navigation of Nonneural Cells, n.d.; Albrecht-Buehler, Guenter (Box 21)
  - Two Structural Principles Concerning the Formation of the Microtubular Skeleton in Centrioles and Basal Bodies, Albrecht-Buehler, Guenter (Box 21)
  - Inactivation of Maize Transposon Mu Suppresses a Mutant Phenotype by Activating an Outward-Reading Promoter Near the End of Mu1, [1991]; Barkan, Alice and Robert A. Martienssen (Box 21)
  - Lysogeny, n.d.; Bertani, G. (Box 21)
  - A Model for the Evolution of Maize and Teosinte, 1978; Bird, Robert McK. (Box 22)
  - Germ-Cell Transfer and Sex Ration in Xenopus laevis, 1965; Blackler, A.W. (Box 22)
  - The Andean Complex, [1973]; Blumenschein, Almiro (Box 22)
  - Conclusions About Knobs Distribution in Eastern South America, 1968; Blumenschein, Almiro (Box 22)
  - Identification of Chromosome Segments That Contribute to the Specificity of Racial Characteristics in Maize, 1964; Blumenschein, Almiro (Box 22)
  - Observed and Expected Heterosis in Interracial Crosses of Maize, [1969]; Blumenschein, Almiro and R. Vencovsky (Box 22)
  - Report of the Collecting Trip to the Território do Amapá (August 30 to September 22, 1966), 4 Oct. 1966; Blumenschein, Almiro (Box 22)
  - The Ultrastructure of the Non-Localized Kinetochores of Luzula and Cyperus, 1971; Braselton, James P. (Box 22)
  - Invariable Genetic Change in Maize Plants Heterozygous for Marbled Aleurone, n.d.; Brink, R. Alexander and Willem H. Weyers (Box 22)
  - The Occurrence of Semi-Sterility in Maize, 1927; Brink, R. Alexander, (Royal Alexander), 1897- (Box 22)
  - Plant Color Effects of Certain Anomalous Forms of the Rr Allele in Maize, n.d.; Brink, R. Alexander and B. Mikula (Box 22)
  - A Stable Somatic Mutation to Colorless From Variegated Pericarp in Maize, 1958; Brink, R. Alexander, (Royal Alexander), 1897- (Box 22)
  - Transpositions of Modulator, a Component of the Variegated Pericarp Allele in Maize, 1959; Brink, R. Alexander and Nancy Worner Van Schaik (Box 22)
  - Chromosome Knob Numbers and Positions, [1960]; Brown, William L. (Box 22)
  - The Southern Dent Corns, 1948; Brown, William L. and Edgar Anderson (Box 22)
  - Chromosome Pairing and the Intercross Method, 1967; Burnham, Charles R., (Charles Russel) (Box 22)
  - A New Method of Using Interchanges as Chromosomal Markers, 1967; Burnham, Charles R., (Charles Russel) (Box 22)
  - The Application of Restriction Fragment Length Polymorphism to Plant Breeding, 1983; Burr, Benjamin, S.V. Evola, and F.A. Burr (Box 22)
  - Defective Transpositions as a Mechanism of Ds-Induced Chromosome Breakage, [1989]; Burr, Benjamin and Frances A. Burr (Box 22)
  - Detection of Maize Controlling Element Events at the Shrunken Locus, [1981]; Burr, Benjamin and Frances A. Burr (Box 22)
  - Ds Controlling Elements of Maize at the Shrunken Locus Are Large and Dissimilar Insertions, Burr, Benjamin and Frances A. Burr (Box 22)
  - A Preliminary Investigation Into the Extent of Restriction Fragment Length Polymorphism in Maize, n.d.; Burr, Benjamin, S.V. Evola, and F.A. Burr (Box 22)
  - Transposable Elements and Genetic Instabilities in Crop Plants, 1981; Burr, Benjamin and Frances A. Burr (Box 22)
  - The Inactive-X Hypothesis and Position Effects in the Mouse, 1963; Cattanach, Bruce M. (Box 22)
  - Cytogenetic Studies Following High Dosage Paternal Irradiation in the Mealy Bug, Planococcus Citri, 1963; Chandra, H. Sharat (Box 22)
  - Identification of a Soluble Salicylic Acid-Binding Protein That May Function in Signal Transduction in the Plant Disease Resistance Response, [1991]; Chen-Zhixiang and Daniel F. Klessig (Box 22)
  - Changes in Phase of an Ac Element at the Waxy Locus Associated with Ac DNA Modification, n.d.; Chomet, Paul S., Susan Wessler, and Stephen L. Dellaporta (Box 22)
  - Characterization of Stable and Metastable Changes of the Maize Transposable Element, Activator, 1988; Chomet, Paul S. (Box 22)
  - Identification of a Regulatory Transposon that Controls the Mutator Transposable Element System in Maize, 1991; Chomet, Paul S., Kristine J. Hardeman, Damon Lisch, Vicki L. Chandler, and Michael Freeling (Box 22)
  - Inactivation of the Maize Transposable Element Activator (Ac) is Associated with its DNA Modification, 1987; Chomet, Paul S., Susan Wessler, and Stephen L. Dellaporta (Box 22)
  - Organization of the Rosy Locus in Drosophila melanogaster: Evidence for a Control Element Adjacent to the Xanthine Dehydrogenase Structural Element, 1976; Chovnick, Arthur, W. Gelbart, M. McCarron, B. Osmond, E.P.M. Candido, and D.L. Baillie (Box 23)
  - Studies on Gene Conversion and its Relationship to Linked Exchange in Drosophila melanogaster, 1971; Chovnick, Arthur, Graeme H. Ballantyne, and David G. Holm (Box 23)
  - Flower Pigments, 1964; Clevenger, Sarah (Box 23)
  - The Aleurone Tissue of Maize as a Genetic Tool, 1977; Coe, Edward H., Jr. (Box 23)
  - Embryo Cells and Their Destinies in the Corn Plant, [1977]; Coe, Edward H., Jr. and M.G. Neuffer (Box 23)
  - Technical Comment: Heritable Repression Due to Paramutation in Maize, [1968]; Coe, Edward H., Jr. (Box 23)
  - Mutable Characters of Drosophila Virilis. I. Reddish-Alpha Body Character, 1928; Demerec, M., (Milislav), 1895-1966 (Box 23)
  - Chromosomal Rearrangements Caused by the Aberrant Transposition of Double Ds Elements are Formed by Ds and Adjacent to Non-Ds Sequences, 1990; Döring, Hans-Peter, I. Pahl, and M. Durany (Box 23)
  - Intracellular Location of Zein in Maize, 1963; Duvick, Donald N. (Box 23)
  - Genetische Untersuchungen an Podospora anserina, 1955; Esser, K. (Box 23)
  - Plant Resources in Colonial America, [1976]; Ewan, Joseph (Box 23)
  - Essential Large Transcripts of the Maize Spm Transposable Element Are Generated By Alternative Splicing, 1989; Fedoroff, Nina, Patrick Masson, George Rutherford, and Jo Ann Banks (Box 23)
  - Genetic and Structural Studies on the Spm-Dependent a-m2 Alleles of the Maize a Locus, 1986; Fedoroff, Nina, Richard Surosky, and Jeffrey A. Kingsbury (Box 23)
  - Maize Transposable Elements, 1987; Fedoroff, Nina (Box 23)
  - Nucleotide Sequence Analysis of the Spm-Dependent a-m2 Alleles of the Maize a Locus and a Model of Spm Regulation, 1986; Fedoroff, Nina and Patrick Masson (Box 23)
  - A Small Celebration -- Review of The Discovery and Characterization of Transposable Elements. The Collected Papers of Barbara McClintock, 1988; Fedoroff, Nina (Box 23)
  - The Suppressor-Mutator Transposable Element of Maize: Genetic Analysis and Cloning of the a-m2 Alleles of the a Locus, 1986; Fedoroff, Nina and Jeffrey A. Kingsbury (Box 23)
  - The Suppressor-Mutator Transposable Element of Maize: Structure and Expression of the Element, 1986; Fedoroff, Nina, Patrick Masson, George Rutherford, and Jo Ann Banks (Box 23)
  - The Suppressor-Mutator Transposable Element of Maize. The a-m2 Alleles, n.d.; Fedoroff, Nina and Jeffrey A. Kingsbury (Box 23)
  - The tnpA and tnpD Gene Products of the Spm Element are Required for Transposition in Tobacco, 1990; Fedoroff, Nina, P. Masson, and M. Strem (Box 23)
  - Controlling Elements in Maize, 1974; Fincham, John R.S. and G.R.K. Sastry (Box 24)
  - Report on the Embo Workshop on Metastable Gene Systems Held in Leeds, 17th to 21st September, 1973, Fincham, John R.S. (Box 24)
  - Transposable Elements and Proviruses, 1981; Finnegan, D.J. (Box 24)
  - Obtaining Haploid Plant Cell Mutants By Selection in Pollen Culture, n.d.; Flashman, S. (Box 24)
  - Allele Variation at the Level of Intragenic Recombination, 1977; Freeling, Michael (Box 24)
  - Radiation-Induced Alcohol Dehydrogenase Mutants in Maize Following Allyl Alcohol Selection of Pollen, 1977; Freeling, Michael and David S.K. Cheng (Box 24)
  - The Extinct Links Between Teosinte and Maize and Their Reconstruction, [197-]; Galinat, Walton C. (Box 24)
  - Lack of Intercellular Suppression of Position-Effect Variegation By Addional Y Chromosomes During Cell Differentiation in Drosophila melanogaster, [1970]; Gearhart, John David (Box 24)
  - Relationships of Drosopterin Content in Transplanted and Host Eyes of Drosophila melanogaster, [1970]; Gearhart, John David (Box 24)
  - Isolation of a Hybrid Plasmid With Homologous Sequences to a Transposing Element of Drosophila melanogaster, 1980; Gehring, Walter J. and Renato Paro (Box 24)
  - Cytoplasmic Male Sterility in Nicotiana, Restoration of Fertility and the Nucleolus, 1978; Gerstel, Daniel U., J.A. Burns, and L.G. Burk (Box 24)
  - On Chromosomes of Unusual Length in Hybrids Between Two Species of Nicotiana, [1964]; Gerstel, Daniel U. and J.A. Burns (Box 24)
  - Phenotypic and Chromosomal Abnormalities Associated With the Introduction of Heterochromatin From Nicotiana otophora into N. tabacum, 1967; Gerstel, Daniel U. and J.A. Burns (Box 24)
  - Spreading of Maize Pachytene Synaptonemal Complexes for Electron Microscopy, 1986; Gillies, C.B. (Box 24)
  - Ultrastructural Analysis of Maize Pachytene Karyotypes by Three Dimensional Reconstruction of the Synaptonemal Complexes, n.d.; Gillies, C.B. (Box 24)
  - The Effect of Lethal Genes on the Non-Disjunctional Classes in Mutual Translocations of Drosophila, 193-; Glass, H. Bentley (Box 24)
  - A History of Plant Genetics at Cold Spring Harbor, [198-]; Glass, H. Bentley (Box 24)
  - A Study of Dominant Mosaic Eye-Color Mutants in Drosophila melanogaster, 1934; Glass, H. Bentley (Box 24)
  - A Study of Factors Influencing Chromosomal Segregation in Translocations of Drosophila melanogaster, 1935; Glass, H. Bentley (Box 24)
  - A Comparison of Chromosome Knob Frequencies Between Sympatric and Allopatric Populations of Teosinte and Maize, 1981; Goodman, Major M. and J.S.C. Smith (Box 24)
  - Races of Maize, [1975?]; Goodman, Major M. and William L. Brown (Box 24)
  - Variation Within Teosinte. II. Numerical Analysis of Chromosome Knob Data, [1980]; Goodman, Major M., J.S.C. Smith, and T.A. Kato Y. (Box 24)
  - Cell and Tissue Cultures of Maize, Green, C.E. (Box 24)
  - Inheritance and Expression of Lysine Plus Threonine Resistance Selected in Maize Tissue Culture, 1982; Green, C.E. and K.A. Hibberd (Box 24)
  - Inheritance of Selected Pathotoxin Resistance in Maize Plants Regenerated From Cell Cultures, 1977; Green, C.E., B.G. Gengenbach, and C.M. Donavan (Box 24)
  - An Analysis of the Adipose Conversion Based on the Study of Fat Cell Clusters in 3T3 Cultures, n.d.; Green, Howard and Olaniyi Kehinde (Box 24)
  - The Regulation of RNA Synthesis in the Fibroblast During Transition From Resting to Growing State, n.d.; Green, Howard and John C. Mauck (Box 24)
  - Mapping a Drosophila melanogaster Controlling Element By Interallelic Crossing Over, [1968]; Green, Melvin M. (Box 24)
  - Unequal Crossing Over and the Genetical Organization of the White Locus of Drosophila melanogaster, 1963; Green, Melvin M. (Box 24)
  - The wm5 and its Derivatives, 1950; Griffen, A.B. and Wilson S. Stone (Box 24)
  - Intergradation Among Latin American Maize Populations Based on an Analysis of Chromosome Knob Frequencies, [1982]; Hanson, W.D. (Box 24)
  - Gene Centers and Gene Utilization, [1976]; Harlan, Jack R. (Box 24)
  - Evolution of Transposons: Natural Selection for Tn5 in Escherichia coli K12, [1982]; Hartl, Daniel L. and Susan W. Biel (Box 24)
  - The Function of the Lampbrush Loops Formed by the Y Chromosome of Drosophila hydei in Spermatocyte Nuclei, 1968; Hess, Oswald (Box 25)
  - A General Mechanism for the Unfolding of the Genetic Programme During Development, [1973]; Holliday, Robin (Box 25)
  - The Mad Mind of Mankind, 1983; Holt, H. John (Box 25)
  - Plant Germplasm Policy, [1976]; Hougas, Robert W. (Box 25)
  - History of U.S. Plant Introduction, [1976]; Hyland, Howard L. (Box 25)
  - Curly Flagellar Mutants in Salmonella, 1958; Iino, Tetsuo (Box 25)
  - Transductional Analysis of Monophastic Types of Salmonella, 1958; Iino, Tetsuo and Joshua Lederberg (Box 25)
  - Transductional Analysis of Phase Variation in Salmonella, 1957; Iino, Tetsuo and Joshua Lederberg (Box 25)
  - Annual Report, 1972; Innes, John (Box 25)
  - Allelic Pairing and Gene Regulation: A Model for the Zeste-White Interaction in Drosophila melanogaster, 1978; Jack, Joseph W. and Burke H. Judd (Box 25)
  - Elements of Regulatory Circuits in Bacteria, 1962; Jacob, François and Jacques Monod (Box 25)
  - Gènes de Structure et Gènes de Régulation dans la Biosynthèse des Protéines, 1959; Jacob, François and Jacques Monod (Box 25)
  - Sur la Nature du Répresseur Assurant L'Immunité des Bactéries Lysogènes, 1962; Jacob, François, Raquel Sussman, and Jacques Monod (Box 25)
  - Differentiation of Evolved Varieties and Primitive Races of Maize of Himalayan and Latin American Distribution, 1971; Jain, H.K. and D. Gupta (Box 25)
  - Genetic Differentiation of Two Himalayan Varieties of Maize, 1972; Jain, H.K. and D. Gupta (Box 25)
  - Pre-Columbian Maize in the Old World From Portuguese Sources, n.d.; Jeffreys, M.D.W. (Box 25)
  - A Visual Assay for Transposon Activity in Tobacco Demonstrates a Positive Effect of Activator (Ac) Dosage on Transposition Frequency, [1988]; Jones, Jonathan D.G., Francine M. Carland, Pal Maliga, and Hugo K. Dooner (Box 25)
  - Intrastrand Exchange as a Possible Mechanism for Instability of Some White Mutants of Drosophila melanogaster, 1967; Judd, B.H. (Box 25)
  - Chromosome Knob Complexes of Maize of America, [1967]; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel and Almiro Blumenschein (Box 25)
  - Chromosome Morphology Studies on Maizes of the Americas, 1972; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel, 1932- (Box 25)
  - Dissertation Research Progress Report, 1974; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel, 1932- (Box 25)
  - Relationships Between Central Mesa of Mexico, Highlands of Guatemala, Costa Rica and Western Panama, 1972; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel, 1932- (Box 25)
  - Some Cytological Studies on Several Mexican Races of Maize, 1964; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel, 1932- (Box 25)
  - Unidentified, n.d.; Kato Yamakake, Takeo Angel, 1932- (Box 25)
    See also Ser.VI, Unidentified
  - Control Circuits for Determination and Transdetermination, 1973; Kauffman, Stuart A. (Box 25)
  - Probing the Component Structure of a Maize Gene with Transposable Controlling Elements, 1979; Kermicle, Jerry L. (Box 25)
  - Fractionnement des Substances qui Interviennent dans la Pigmentation des Yeux de Drosophila melanogaster, 1937; Khouvine, Yvonne and Boris Ephrussi (Box 25)
  - Spermatogenesis in Bombyx mori. II. The Ultrastructure of Synapsed Bivalents, 1971; King, Robert C. and Hiromu Akai (Box 25)
  - The Morphogenesis of Insect-Induced Galls on Higher Plants, [1973]; Krikorian, Abraham D. and William W. Donald (Box 25)
  - The Heuristics of Nature: The Plausible Mutation of DNA, 1980; Lenat, Douglas B. (Box 26)
  - The Relation of Repeats to Position Effect in Drosophila melanogaster, 1945; Lewis, Edward B., 1918-2004 (Box 26)
  - Retroposon Evolution, [1990]; McClure, Marcella A. (Box 26)
  - Sequence Analysis of Eukaryotic Retroid Proteins, 1990; McClure, Marcella A. (Box 26)
  - Genic and Nongenic Transmission of Mutator Activity, 1946; Mampell, Klaus (Box 26)
  - Genes that Control Development, 1981; Marx, Jean L. (Box 26)
  - Cell Division and the Determination Phase of Cytodifferentiation in Plants, 1974; Meins, Frederick, Jr. (Box 26)
  - A Kinetic Model Describing the Conversion of Organized Teratoma Tissues of Tobacco to the Unorganized State in Culture, n.d.; Meins, Frederick, Jr. (Box 26)
  - Mechanisms Underlying the Persistence of Tumor Autonomy in Crown-Gall Disease, Meins, Frederick, Jr. (Box 26)
  - Mechanisms Underlying Tumor Transformation and Tumor Reversal in Crown-Gall, a Neoplastic Disease of Higher Plants, 1973; Meins, Frederick, Jr. (Box 26)
  - Temperature Sensitive Expression of Auxin-Autotrophy by Crown-Gall Teratoma Cells of Tobacco, n.d.; Meins, Frederick, Jr. (Box 26)
  - Unstable DNA Elements in the Chromosomes of Drosophila, 1980; Meselson, Matthew, Pamela Dunsmuir, Miriam Schweber, and Paul Bingham (Box 26)
  - Chromosome Behavior, Inheritance and Sex Determination in Sciara, [1938]; Metz, Charles W. (Box 26)
  - Chromosome Structure in the Salivary Glands of Sciara, [1934]; Metz, Charles W. (Box 26)
  - Studies on Sex Determination and the Sex Chromosome Mechanism in Sciara, 1931; Metz, Charles W. and M. Louise Schmuck (Box 26)
  - Knob Structures in Maize, 1964; Monteiro, Warton (Box 26)
  - A Variable Phenotype Associated with the Fourth Chromosome of Drosophila melanogaster and Affected by Heterochromatin, 1947; Morgan, L.V. (Box 26)
  - Maintenance of a Drosophila Stock Center, In Connection with Investigations on the Constitution of the Germinal Material in Relation to Heredity, 1943; Morgan, T.H., Helen Redfield, and L.V. Morgan (Box 26)
  - Synaptonemal Complex Analysis of Mouse Chromosomal Rearrangements. IV. Synapsis and Synaptic Adjustment in Two Paracentric Inversions, 1981; Moses, M.J., P.A. Poorman, T.H. Roderick, and M.T. Davisson (Box 26)
  - Historical Review of the Development of Triticale, 1974; Müntzing, Arne (Box 26)
  - Biochemical Consequences of an Insertion of the Receptor for Spm at the Bronze-1 Locus in Maize, [1983]; Nelson, Oliver E., Jr. and Anita S. Klein (Box 26)
  - Evidence Implicating the Spm Family of Transposable Elements in the Mosaic Pericarp (P-mo) Allele of Maize, [1989]; Nelson, Oliver Evans, Jr., 1920- (Box 26)
  - Exploiting Transposable Elements to Study the Expression of a Maize Gene, n.d.; Nelson, Oliver E., Jr., John W. Schiefelbein, Douglas B. Furtek, Victor Raboy, Jo Ann Banks, and Nina V. Fedoroff (Box 26)
  - Heterogeneous Flavonoid Glucosytransferases in Colored Derivatives from a Controlling Element-Suppressed Bronze Mutant in Maize, 1978; Nelson, Oliver E., Jr. and Hugo K. Dooner (Box 26)
  - Molecular Characterization of Suppressor-Mutator (Spm)-Induced Mutations at the Bronze-1 Locus in Maize: The bz-m13 Alleles, Nelson, Oliver E., Jr., John W. Schiefelbein, Douglas B. Furtek, Victor Raboy, Jo Ann Banks, and Nina V. Fedoroff (Box 26)
  - Mutant Gene That Changes Protein Composition and Increases Lysine Content of Maize Endosperm, 1958?; Nelson, Oliver E., Jr., Edwin T. Mertz, and Lynn S. Bates (Box 26)
  - Tissue-Specific Effects of Maize Bronze Gene Promoter Mutations Induced by Dsl Insertion and Excision, [1989]; Nelson, Oliver E., Jr., Thomas D. Sullivan, and John W. Schiefelbein, Jr. (Box 26)
  - The Waxy Locus in Maize. II. The Location of the Controlling Element Mutants, 1968; Nelson, Oliver Evans, Jr., 1920- (Box 26)
  - The Waxy Locus in Maize. III. Effect of Structural Heterozygosity on Intragenic Recombination and Flanking Marker Assortment, 1975; Nelson, Oliver Evans, Jr., 1920- (Box 26)
  - Crossingover in Heterozygotes Carrying Different Mutable Alleles at the A1 Locus in Maize, 1965; Neuffer, M.G. (Box 26)
  - Plant Transposable Elements --2 Folders, n.d.; Nevers, Patricia, Nancy S. Shepherd, and Heinz Saedler (Box 27)
  - A Note on Types of Maize in Peru, n.d.; Nicholson, G. Edward (Box 27)
  - Chromosomes and Kinetochores Do More in Mitosis Than Previously Thought, 1987; Nicklas, R. Bruce (Box 27)
  - Mitosis, 1970; Nicklas, R. Bruce (Box 27)
  - The Non-Random Chromosome Segregation in Spermatocytes of Gryllotalpa hexadactyla, 1968; Nicklas, R. Bruce and René Camenzind (Box 27)
  - Riddle of the Giant Panda's Phylogeny: A Molecular Solution, 1985; O'Brien, Stephen J., W.G. Nash, D.E. Wildt, M.E. Bush, and R.E. Benveniste (Box 27)
  - On the Evolution of Genome Organization in Mammals, 1984; O'Brien, Stephen J., Hector N. Seuanez, and James E. Womack (Box 27)
  - Tracing the Natural History of the Cheetah: A Genetic Basic for Species Vulnerability, 1984; O'Brien, Stephen J., M.E. Roelke, L. Marker, et al. (Box 27)
  - Cytogenetics: Conclusive Report of Progress for 1962-1965, Aug. 1965; Ohta, Yasuo (Box 27)
  - Experimental Project with Detailed Procedures, 1-May-63; Ohta, Yasuo (Box 27)
  - Quantitative Aspects of the Cytogenetics of Maize, [1965]; Ohta, Yasuo (Box 27)
  - Changes in the Inducibility of Galactokinase and Beta-Galactosidase During Inhibition of Growth in E. Coli, Paigen, Kenneth (Box 27)
  - Cooperative Infection by Host Modified Lambdaphage, n.d.; Paigen, Kenneth and Herbert Weinfeld (Box 27)
  - Evidence for a New Intermediate State of the Viral Chromosome During Cooperative Infection by Host-Modified Lambdaphage, n.d.; Paigen, Kenneth and Herbert Weinfeld (Box 27)
  - Genetic Control of Enzymes in Differentiation, 1963; Paigen, Kenneth (Box 27)
  - Genetic Factors Affecting Enzyme Activity, [1970]; Paigen, Kenneth and James Felton (Box 27)
  - Genetic Factors in Developmental Regulation, Paigen, Kenneth (Box 27)
  - A Locus Determining the Beta-Galactosidase Developmental Program in Mouse Liver, 1974; Paigen, Kenneth, Miriam Meisler, James Felton, and Verne Chapman (Box 27)
  - The Molecular Genetics of Mammalian Glucuronidase, 1974; Paigen, Kenneth, Richard T. Swank, and Shiro Tomino (Box 28)
  - Mutations Affecting Enzyme Realization, n.d.; Paigen, Kenneth and Roger Ganschow (Box 28)
  - On the Regulation of DNA Transcription, n.d.; Paigen, Kenneth (Box 28)
  - Temporal Genes and Developmental Programs, 1976; Paigen, Kenneth (Box 28)
  - Temporal Genes and Other Developmental Regulators in Mammals, 1979; Paigen, Kenneth (Box 28)
  - Two Linked Genes Showing a Similar Timing of Expression in Mice, [1960]; Paigen, Kenneth and Werner K. Noell (Box 28)
  - A New Device to Increase Depth of Focus of Microscope Objectives for Use in Photomicrography, 1952; Pence, Roy J. (Box 28)